Guide to the Oversize Manuscripts Collection 1648-2018 MS OS
New-York Historical Society
- Series I. Individual Oversize Manuscripts, 1648-1942
  - [Y-1783, January] Letter of Marque, 1783 January 2 (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1783, January (Marque))
  - [Y-1784, May] Return- West Point (From Sebastian Bauman Papers), 1784 May 31 (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1784, May (Bauman))
    Sebastian Bauman Correspondence, 1775-1795 (bulk 1779-1781)
  - [Y-1784, June, July] Watts, Robert and John- Deeds, 1784 June 16, July 1 (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1784, June, July (Watts))
  - [Y-1784, June] Rumbout Patent and Copy, 1784 June 25 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1784, June (Rumbout))
  - [Y-1784, December] Deed- Van Cortlandt Family, 1784 December 15 (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1784, December (Van Cortlandt))
  - [Y-1785] Society of Cincinnati- Howe, Bezaleel (Oversize small, Folder Y-1785 (Howe))
    Bezaleel Howe Papers
  - [Y-1785, December] Samuel B. Webb and James Fairlie- Membership Certificate, Society of Cincinnati, 1785 December 10 (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1785, December (Webb))
    Conditions Governing Access:
    Contains Presidential Signature.
  - [Y-1786] Deed Between Executors of Yates and Glen (Oversize small, Folder Y-1786 (Yates))
  - [Y-1786, February] Watts, Robert and John- Deed, 1786 February 19 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1786, February (Watts))
  - [Y-1786, February] Heyward, Thomas- Power of Attorney, 1786 February 6 (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1786, February (Heyward))
  - [Y-1786, May] John Laurance Estate (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1786, May (Laurance))
    John Laurance Papers
  - [Y-1786, May] Deed- William P. Smith, 1786 May 5 (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1786, May (Smith))
  - [Y-1786, May] Indenture re Elizabeth Carpender's Will and Estate, 1786 May 6 (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1786, May (Carpender))
  - [Y-1786, June] Grant to Steuben from N.Y. State, 1786 June 27 (Oversize large, Folder Y-1786, June (Steuben))
  - [Y-1786, August] Land patent to Cornelius Ray, signed by George Clinton, 1786 August 14 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1786, August (Ray))
  - [Y-1787, March] Petition of Garret Rapezje et al., 1787 March 5 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1787, March (Rapezje))
  - [Y-1787, April] Mutual Assurance (Original), 1787, April 3 (Oversize large, Folder Y-1787, April (Mutual))
  - [Y-1787, December] Barclay Indenture, 1787 December 25 (Oversize large, Folder Y-1787, December (Barclay))
  - [Y-1788] Verplanck, Samuel- Deeds (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1788 (Verplanck))
  - [Y-1788] Rivington, James- Mortgage, 1788 March 4 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1788 (Rivington))
  - [Y-1789, April] Greenwood Family, Coat of Arms (description of museum object 1969.4), 1789 April 11 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1789, April (Greenwood))
  - [Y-1789, September] Watts, John- Exemption of Will, 1789 September 16 (Oversize large, Folder Y-1789, September (Watts))
  - [Y-1790, May] Jones, Gardner - Indenture between Gardner and Sarah Jones and Samuel Jones, 1790 May 5 (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1790, May (Jones))
  - [Y-1790, July] Land Grant- Brutus Township, Montgomery Co., 1790 July 8 (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1790, July (Brutus))
  - [Y-1792] U.S. Treasury Dept. Accounts, circa 1792 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1792 (Treasury))
  - [Y-1792, January] Albany Library Petition, 1792 January 31 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1792, January (Albany))
  - [Y-1792, June] Watts, John Jr.- Deed, 1792 June 25 (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1792, June (Watts))
  - [Y-1792, December] Randall Fire Insurance Policy, 1792 December 12 (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1792, December (Randall))
  - [Y-1793] Bowne and Robinson (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1793 (Bowne))
  - [Y-1793] Indenture between Aaron Burr and Roger Strong for land in New Jersey (Oversize small, Folder Y-1793 (Burr))
  - [Y-1793, March] Wygant- Deed, 1793 March 28 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1793, March (Wygant))
  - [Y-1793] Deed. John Peter and Elizabeth DeLancey to Philip Livingston and others (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1793 (DeLancey))
    One deed from the DeLanceys to Philip Livingston, John Watts, Thomas Buchanan, Gulian Verplanck, James Watson, Moses Rogers, James Farquhar, Richard Harison, and Daniel Ludlow, for land in the 1st Ward of New York City, bounded by Broadway on the east, by Temple Street on the west, by Thames Street on the south, and by Little Queen Street on the north.
    Gift of Winifred Gulick, 2015.
  - [Y-1795] Exemplification of the Will of Archibald Kennedy (Oversize large, Folder Y-1795 (Kennedy))
  - [Y-1795, October] Noble to Lawrence and Fish- Deed, 1795 October 21 (Oversize large, Folder Y-1795, October (Noble))
  - [Y-1796, March] Rutgers, Robert- Commission, 1796 March 31 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1796, March (Rutgers))
  - [Y-1797, February] Chassanis, Peter, 1797 February 15 (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1797, February (Chassanis))
  - [Y-1799, January] Grant to Lawrence, 1799 January 7 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1799, January (Lawrence))
  - [Y-1799, January] Bond for William Sing, 1799 January 10 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1799, January (Sing))
  - [Y-1800, February] Grant to Lawrence, 1800 February 19 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1800, February (Lawrence))
  - [Y-1800, November] Hoosick Indenture, 1800 November 24 (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1800, November (Hoosick))
  - [Y-1801, August] A List of Prisoners Confined in a City Jail, NY, 1801 August 26 (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1801, August (Prisoners))
  - [Y-1802, October] Corporation for the Relief of Widows, 1802 October 16 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1802, October (Widows))
  - [Y-1803] Authorization for the Sale of Louisiana (Contains Napoleon's Signature) (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1803 (Louisiana))
  - [Y-1803] Log of Ship Geo, Barclay (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1803 (Barclay))
  - [Y-1803, October] Estate of James Duane, 1803 October 11 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1803, October (Duane))
  - [Y-1803, December] Remsen, John- Christmas Poem, 1803 December 25 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1803, December (Remsen))
  - [Y-1805] Tompkins Appointment to Judge (Oversize small, Folder Y-1805 (Tompkins))
  - [Y-1806 February] Deed for land in New York City from the estate of James Lawrence (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1806, February (Lawrence))
  - [Y-1806] Land Deed between Smith, Denyse Family, and Stewart (Oversize small, Folder Y-1806 (Smith))
  - [Y-1807] Patents and Descriptions- Orange Webb (Contains Presidential Signature), circa 1807 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1807 (Orange Webb))
    Conditions Governing Access
  - [Y-1807] Fulton, Robert- Steam Engine Drawing (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1807 (Fulton))
  - [Y-1807, April] Crew Lists (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1807, April (Crew))
  - [Y-1808, February] Fulton, Robert- (Clermont), 1808 February 2 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1808, February (Fulton))
    Robert R. Livingston Papers
  - [Y-1808, October] Fulton, Robert- Drawing- (Raritan), 1808 October 22 (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1808, October (Fulton))
  - [Y-1809, March] Ships "Astrea" and "Thomas" (Oversize small, Folder Y-1809, March (Ships))
  - [Y-1809, September] Brig Statira Sea Letter, 1809 September 19 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1809, September (Brig Statira))
  - [Y-1810] James Lawrence (Oversize small, Folder Y-1810 (Lawrence))
  - [Y-1811, February] Corporation for the Relief of Widows, 1811 February 1 (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1811, February (Widows))
  - [Y-1812, April] White and Haydock- Marriage, 1812 April 9 (Oversize large, Folder Y-1812, April (White))
  - [Y-1812, June] Indenture- Elizabeth Hamilton, 1812 June 9 (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1812, June (Hamilton))
  - [Y-1813, January] Cutting and Fulton, 1813 January 25 (Oversize large, Folder Y-1813, January (Cutting))
  - [Y-1813, June] Commission of Charles Wardell as 1st Lieutenant of 2nd Troop, 3rd Regiment, 1st Brigade of Artillery, 1813 June 29 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1813, June (Wardell))
  - [Y-1814, April] Bloomingdale Reformed Church, 1814 April 29 (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1814, April (Bloomingdale))
  - [Y-1814, December] Commission, 1814 December 10 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1814, December (Commission))
  - [Y-1816] Washington College- William Nisbit (Oversize small, Folder Y-1816 (Nisbit))
  - [Y-1817] Patents and Descriptions- Orange Webb (Contains Presidential Signature), circa 1817 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1817 (Orange Webb))
  - [Y-1819] Grim- Notes on City Hall (Photostats) (Oversize small, Folder Y-1819 (Grim, Photostats))
  - [Y-1819] Grim- Notes on City Hall (Originals) (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1819 (Grim, Originals))
  - [Y-1823] Peter Smith Conveyance (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1823 (Smith))
  - [Y-1823, May] Corporation for the Relief of Widows, 1823 May 3 (Oversize large, Folder Y-1823, May (Widows))
  - [Y-1826, April] Indenture between Peter Gerard Stuyvesant and his wife Helen and Henry Rankin, 1826 April 10 (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1826, April (Stuyvesant))
  - [Y-1829] Ship Extio (Oversize small, Folder Y-1829 (Extio))
  - [Y-1829, August] Maxwell, Hugh, 1829 August 22 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1829, August (Maxwell))
  - [Y-1831] John James Audubon Bird Descriptions (Oversize small, Folder Y-1831 (Audubon))
    Gift of Dr. Thomas Perry, Jr., 1983 or 1984
  - [Y-1833, December] Resolution of Anti-Slavery Convention, 1833 December 6 (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1833, December (Resolution))
  - [Y-1834] Riots (Oversize medium, Folder 1834 (Riots))
  - [Y-1835, October] Isaac Bush Letter, 1835 October 30 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1835, October (Bush))
  - [Y-1835, November] Whaleman's Shipping Paper (Oversize small, Folder Y-1835, November (Whaleman))
  - [Y-1836, January] John Parker Certificate- Texas, 1836 January 26 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1836, January (Parker))
  - [Y-1836, July] Peake, Frederick L., 1836 July 1 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1836, July (Peake))
  - [Y-1837] Audubon, John James- List of Birds of America (Oversize large, Folder Y-1837 (Audubon))
  - [Y-1839, November 20] Corporation for Relief of Widows (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1839, November (Widows))
  - [Y-1840] U.S. Navy Fire Bill (Oversize small, Folder Y-1840 (Navy))
  - [Y-1840, December] Election Certificate, 1840 December 2 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1840, December (Election))
  - [Y-1844] Meteorological Register (Oversize small, Folder Y-1844 (Meteorological))
  - [Y-1845] Breed and Bowne- Certificate of Marriage (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1845 (Breed))
  - [Y-1845] Meteorological Register (Oversize small, Folder Y-1845 (Meteorological))
  - [Y-1846] Meteorological Register (Oversize small, Folder Y-1846 (Meteorological))
  - [Y-1848] Meteorological Register (Oversize small, Folder Y-1848 (Meteorological))
  - [Y-1850] Coroner's Account (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1850 (Coroner))
  - [Y-1850, January, September] Lind-Barnum Preliminary Agreement and Final Contract, 1850 January 9, September 14 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1850, January (Lind-Barnum))
  - [Y-1853] Brown, Jesse- Diploma (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1853 (Brown))
  - [Y-1853, October] Castle Garden- Poem (Oversize small, Folder Y-1853, October (Castle Garden))
  - [Y-1856] Schwartzwalder, Ameia (Oversize small, Folder Y-1856 (Schwartzwalder))
  - [Y-1857] Subscription List to the Numismatical History of the U.S. (Oversize small, Folder Y-1857 (Numismatical))
  - [Y-1858] Marriage Certificate- Salem H. Smith and Lucy Bassler (Oversize small, Folder Y-1858 (Smith))
  - [Y-1860] Certificate that Accompanied Bullet Mold (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1860 (Mold))
  - [Y-1861] Wilde, Edward S. (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1861 (Wilde))
  - [Y-1861, July] Murray, Robert, 1861 July 22 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1861, July (Murray))
  - [Y-1861, August] Alert Hose Co., No. 3 resolutions re: William Moir Smith + frame, 1861 August 22 (Oversize large, Folder Y-1861 August (Smith))
    Preamble and resolutions adopted at a special meeting of Alert Hose Co., No. 3, at the Carriage House in Brooklyn W.D. memorializing their fellow firefighter William Moir Smith who died at Richmond, Virginia, of wounds from the battle of Bull Run on July 21, 1861. Smith was a member of the 71st Regiment, Company A. Signed by H.A. Ransford, foreman, and W.A. Price, secretary.
    Purchase, Swann Galleries, Sale #2391, Lot 117, September 17, 2015.
  - [Y-1862] Ericsson, John- Resolution by New York State Assembly (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1862 (Ericsson))
    NHSC- John Ericsson Collection, 1831-1893 (bulk 1862-1888)
  - [Y-1862, May] Sketch of a Military Reconnaissance- Portsmouth, 1862 May 27-29 (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1862, May (Portsmouth))
    NHSC- General James Barnes Collection, 1827-1993
  - [Y-1862] Map of the Rebel Intrenched Camp near Norfolk (Oversize small, Folder Y-1862 (Rebel))
  - [Y-1862] National Academy of Design (Oversize small, Folder Y-1862 (Design))
  - [Y-1862] Conover family certificates, 1862-1894 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1862 (Conover))
    Includes 8 documents: 2 graduation certificates from Rutgers Female Institute to Lizzie A. Conover (1862, 1865); Certificate of membership in the Free and Accepted Masons, Holland Lodge, No. 8, to John T. Conover (1864); Graduation certificate from Van Norman Institute to Mary Conover Jones (1888); Graduation certificate from Columbia College, School of Mines, to Edward Marwedel Jones (1894); and 3 oval pictures (drawings?) of John, Lizzie, Mary (identified by donor; not noted on the objects). (Gift, Richard K. Lewis, 2019)
  - [Y-1863] Emancipation Proclamation (Leland-Boker Autographed Edition) (Oversize small, Folder Y-1863 (Emancipation))
    Contains Presidential Signature
  - [Y-1863, March] Swartwout, George H., 1863 March 17 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1863, March (Swartwout))
  - [Y-1863, December] Couring, Rufus B.- Attorney Appointment, 1863 December 8 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1863, December (Couring))
  - [Y-1864, May] National Academy of Design, 1864 May 11 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1864, May (Design))
  - [Y-undated] My Friends at Libby Prison [certificate signed by prisoners], circa 1860s (Oversize medium, Folder Y-Undated (Libby))
  - [Y-1865, April] NYC Chamber of Commerce- Memorial to A. Lincoln, 1865 April 22 (Oversize large, Folder Y-1865, April (Lincoln))
  - [Y-1865 May] Presidential Pardons of Confederate Soldiers (George Cronan, N.S. Rector, R.A. Rutherford), 1865 May 5, 12 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1865, May (Cronan))
  - [Y-1867] Sturges Testimonial (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1867 (Sturges))
  - [Y-1871] Key, Calvin Jones- Diplomas (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1871 (Key))
  - [Y-1872, May] Meteorological Record, 1872 May 29 (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1872, May (Meteorological))
  - [Y-1874, November] Sigel, Franz- Testimonial, 1874 November 18 (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1874, November (Sigel))
  - [Y-1875] Isaac Peck Family Papers (Oversize small, Folder Y-1875 (Peck))
    Isaac Peck family papers, 1799-1907 (bulk 1830-1890)Emma Thursby papers, 1706-1940 (bulk 1880-1920
  - [Y-1878] Crommelin Family Tree (Oversize large, Folder Y-1878 (Crommelin))
  - [Y-1879] Thursby, Emma (Oversize small, Folder Y-1879 (Thursby))
    Emma Thursby papers, 1706-1940 (bulk 1880-1920)
  - [Y-1880] Osgood, Harris and Co. (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1880 (Osgood))
  - [Y-1883] Stevens, J.A.- Evacuation Day Celebration (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1883 (Stevens))
    Papers, 1811-1885- John Austin Stevens
  - [Y-1884] Electoral Votes (Oversize small, Folder Y-1884 (Votes))
  - [Y-1885] Mabbott, J. Milton (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1885 (Mabbott))
  - [Y-1885] Thursby, Emma (Oversize small, Folder Y-1885 (Thursby))
  - [Y-1886] New York State Society of Cincinnati- Howe, George B. (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1886 (Howe))
  - [Y-1893] Ward, Aaron - Certificate, Society of Colonial Wars (Oversize small, Folder Y-1893 (Ward))
  - [Y-1896, May] Austin, Mary North, 1896 May 12 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1896, May (Austin))
  - [Y-1898] Sherman, Thomas G. - Passport, 1898 June 18 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1898, June (Sherman))
  - [Y-1899, March] Helen M. Gould, 1899 March 24 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1899, March (Gould))
    Helen Miller Gould Shepard papers, 1814-1941
  - [Y-1900] Tuller, Loren W.- Military Certificate (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1900 (Tuller))
  - [Y-1904] Helen M. Gould, China Testimonial (Oversize medium, Folder Y-1904 (Gould))
  - [Y-1905, December] Bonaparte, Charles Joseph, 1905 December 7 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1905, December (Bonaparte))
  - [Y-1907-1908] Sara Hoexter Blumenthal (Oversize small, Folder Y-1907 (Blumenthal))
    Sara Hoexter Blumenthal papers, 1910-1951
  - [Y-1914, December] Harbord, James, 1914 December 31 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1914, December (Harbord))
    Related Materials
    James Harbord Papers and BV Harbord
  - [Y-1919] Arthur M. Anderson (Oversize small, Folder Y-1919 (Anderson))
  - [Y-1920] Mabel Davison Memorial items, 1920, 1940 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1920 (Davison))
    Medaille de la Reconnaissance Francaise, with related certificate, awarded to Mabel Davison for her care of blinded French soldiers during World War I. Also a related certificate to Davison from the American Fund for French Wounded. These items, with a placard also in the folder, were originally framed together in 1940. They were a gift to N-YHS in June 1940 by Charles Stewart Davison in the context of the opening year of World War II. See Davison's contextual June 1940 letter in the institutional archives (General Correspondence, Box 191, folder 2). The items were unframed, and the frame discarded, by conservator Alan Balicki in September 2022.
  - [Y-1931] Gardner Institute (New York) diploma to Nina Woods Parke, 1931 June 5 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1931, June (Parke))
    Certificate awarded for the completion of studies in the College Preparatory Course. Signed by principal Mary Elizabeth Masland. Stamped with seal that reads "The Gardner School, 1857." With tied ribbon that was presumably used to hold the document in rolled form. (Historical note: Also know as the Gardner School for Girls, the organization was founded in 1857. At the time of this certificate, and since 1916, it was located at 11 East 51st Street in New York City. Masland had been its principal since 1910. The Institute closed in 1949.)
    Gift of Nina Hill Hopkins, September 2018.
  - [Y-1939] Inauguration of Washington Commemorative Stamps, 1939 April 30 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1939 (Stamps))
    Item is a sheet of 50 3 cents stamps issued on April 30, 1939, for the "Sesquicentennial of the inauguration of Washington as first president." Sheet (#22365) is mounted to paper backing, with contextual information, indicating that the sheet was sold by New York City postmaster Albert Goldman to N-YHS Director Alexander J. Wall on the first day of issue. Goldman signed and dated the sheet and signed the backing.
  - [Y-1942?] Drawings by Violet B. Alvarez, circa 1942 (Oversize small, Folder Y-1942? (Alvarez))
    Includes a watercolor of Trinity Church in lower Manhattan, which appears to be initialed VBA. With the drawing are documents that seem likely to have come from the backing of the previously framed drawing. These documents include a newspaper clipping with context and likely placing the provenance of the drawing as a gift from the artist Violet B. Alvarez to Albert Ulmann (1861-1948); with the clipping is a drawing of an artist, both mounted on paper signed by Alvarez and dated August 1942.
    Uncertain. A note included with the documents states that the gift was from Mrs. Joseph F. Simmons on July 12, 1939, but this seems incorrect: the drawing was was not recorded in the accession ledger of that date with Simmons's other gifts, and the 1939 date is inconsistent with the artist's 1942 date.
  - [Y-1942] Zenger Memorial Fund (Oversize small, Folder Y-1942 (Zenger))
  - [Y-undated] Rules of NYC Firemen (Oversize small, Folder Y-Undated (Firemen))
- Series II. Oversize Manuscripts From Other Collections, 1714-2018
  - [Y-AHMC Ammon Family] Papers, 1831-1911 (Oversize medium)
    Ten documents related to the family of Ernst Ammon and Maria Keim Ammon, German immigrants who lived in New York City in the mid 19th century. Includes birth, marriage, confirmation, and citizenship certificates, a deed, and National Guard payslips.
  - [Y-AHMC Arndt, Abraham] Commision to Abraham Arndt Esqauire as first Judge of the County of Montgomery, 1801 January 24 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-AHMC Ashmun, George] Portrait and letter, 1841 November 6, undated (Oversize small)
  - [Y-AHMC Brookes Family] Deeds and mortgages, 1751-1802 (Oversize large)
  - [Y-AHMC Brooklyn, NY] Abstract of Title, Maps, 1801-1856 (Oversize large)
  - [Y-AHMC Brookman, Thomas] Writ, 1762 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-AHMC Buffalo, NY] Improvement of Roads, Accounts, 1812-1814 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-AHMC Buffalo, NY] Harbor Construction, Payroll, 1838-1839 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-AHMC Charlotte County, N.Y.] Land Grant, 1772 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-AHMC Coenties Slip] Deeds, 1756-1792 (Oversize large)
  - [Y-AHMC Colebrooke & Rogers] Account book, 1729 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-AHMC Cooper, Isaac] Deed for land in Bangor, 1815 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-AHMC Cothonneau, William] Estate inventory, 1718 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-AHMC Davey, Peter] Eagle Fire Company Insurance Policy, 1806 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-AHMC Eaton, Charles P] Photograph (2 copies), undated (Oversize small)
  - [Y-AHMC Howell, Jacob] Receipt roll of Howell's Company, Farrington's Regiment, 1814 October 22 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-AHMC Jamaica (West Indies)] Indenture between Eilardus Westerlo, Catherine Westerlo, and Richard Grant, for a sugar plantation, 1784 July 6 (Oversize medium)
  - [Y-AHMC Johnson, William M.] Map and deed, 1845 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-AHMC Kroaker] Handwritten newspaper from Lyme, Conn., 1873 (Oversize medium)
  - [Y-AHMC Long Island City (New York, N.Y.)] Lawrence family deeds, 1639-1759 (Oversize medium)
  - [Y-AHMC McConnell, James] Legal documents for assignment of a judgment, 1816 August 26 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-AHMC McFarlan, Robert] Commission as judge in the Court of Common Pleas, Montgomery County, N.Y., 1798 March 27 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-AHMC McKune, Robert] Letters patent as a repacker, inspector of beef and culler of staves in Orange County, N.Y.], 1803 January 15 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-AHMC Melyn Papers] Mandamus, 1648 April 25 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-AHMC Morse, Samuel F.B.] Drawing of first register for Morse's magnetic telegraph), 1846 (Oversize small)
    General Note
    Drawn and signed by John Stokell, New York. Signed as presented to N-YHS by William Davis, July 1852.
  - [Y-AHMC Mott, Valentine] Diplomas & certificates, 1806-1833 [4 items: one in folder + three in frames] (Oversize small)
  - [Y-AHMC Smith, John (active 18th century)] Family papers, 1774-1801 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-AHMC Stevens, William H.] Appointment as Consul General, 1901 May 13 (Oversize small)
    Access Restrictions
    Contains President William McKinley's signature. Includes two envelopes.
  - [Y-AHMC Stuyvesant deed] Peter Stuyvesant deed to Govert Loockermans, 1664 May 20 (Oversize small)
    Includes a frame made of wood from the famed pear tree Stuyvesant planted at what became the northeast corner of Third Avenue and East 13th Street in Manhattan. For fuller details, and to request these items for research, read their catalog record.
  - [Y-AHMC Wood, Fernando] "To the People of Louisiana, their Executive and Representatives... " (appointment and certification of New York City's Commissioners to the South), 1861 January 29 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-AHMC Yorkville Clock], Neighbors Restoring the Historic Yorkville Clock records, 1998 (Oversize medium)
    Folder 3 of 3. Includes the three elevations and detail plans for the clock refurbishment prepared by Historical Arts & Casting.
  - [Y- Arnold, Abraham and Percy], 1897-1918 (Oversize small)
  - [Y-Astor Family Papers], 1790-1877 (Oversize small, medium, large)
    Other Finding Aids